{
  "title": "4.1",
  "definitions": {
    "HASTEN": {
      "word": "HASTEN",
      "phonetic": "(hAs'-:m)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to go quickly, speed, hurry; speed up </p><p>Note the pronunciation. The <i class=“def-ital\">t</i> is silent. </p><p>To HASTEN is to move or act quickly. </p><p>“The policeman HASTENED to the scene of the crime.” </p><p>“He HASTENED to add that the price did not include the tax.” </p><p>To HASTEN something is to speed it up, to make it go faster. </p><p>“The general tried to HASTEN the enemy’s defeat by sending more soldiers into the battle.” </p><p>HASTE is quickness or speed, especially careless speed. </p><p>“In his HASTE to leave he forgot to take his jacket.” </p><p>Something which is HASTY is done quickly, often too quickly. </p><p>“They decided to have a party at the last minute, and then made some HASTY preparations for it.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: HASTE, n. HASTY, adj.</p>"
    },
    "FAMINE": {
      "word": "FAMINE",
      "phonetic": "(fam'-:m)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">an extreme shortage of food </p><p>A FAMINE is a severe lack of food in an area. </p><p>“When it didn’t rain for months, the crops all died, and FAMINE resulted.” </p><p>FAMINE is also occasionally used about severe shortages of other kinds of things. </p><p>“The charity was suffering from a FAMINE of contributions; no one was giving it any money.” </p><p>A related adjective is FAMISHED, which means <i class=“def-ital\">extremely hungry</i>, <i class=“def-ital\">starving</i>. </p><p>“After six days without food we were FAMISHED.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: FAMISHED,adj.</p>"
    },
    "EXCURSION": {
      "word": "EXCURSION",
      "phonetic": "(ek-sker'-zh:;in)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a short journey, pleasure trip; a digression </p><p> An EXCURSION is a short trip, usually made for pleasure as part of a group, with the intention of returning to the starting point. </p><p>“We had a pleasant EXCURSION to the country last weekend.” </p><p>“They made their annual EXCURSION to the seashore.” </p><p>EXCURSION is also occasionally used to mean digression, a brief departure from the main idea or the main goal. </p><p>“We could never follow him when he went off on one of his EXCURSIONS into higher mathematics.”</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">ex-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "DERANGED": {
      "word": "DERANGED",
      "phonetic": "(d:;i-rAnjd')",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">crazy, insane </p><p>To DERANGE something is to put it out of proper order, to <i class=“def-ital\">disarrange</i> it. As an adjective, DERANGED is used about people whose minds are not working properly, and means <i class=“def-ital\">insane</i>. </p><p>“The DERANGED man wandered across the highway in the middle of rush hour.” </p><p>“The DERANGED killer said that he heard voices telling him whom to murder.” </p><p>The most common wrong answer on the Pretest is <i class=“def-ital\">unhappy</i>. Great sorrow can sometimes cause a person to become DERANGED, but someone who is <i class=“def-ital\">unhappy</i> is not necessarily insane. </p><p>Other forms of the word: DERANGE,v.</p>"
    },
    "DECREE": {
      "word": "DECREE",
      "phonetic": "(d:;i-krE')",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">an order, edict </p><p>A DECREE is an order, given by a ruler, judge, or anyone in power, which is to be obeyed just like a law. </p><p>“The king’s DECREE that property taxes were to be raised did not increase his popularity.” </p><p>“We tried every way we could think of to get around Dad’s DECREE that we were to be in bed by nine o’clock.” </p><p>DECREE is also a verb which means “to give an order.” </p><p>“The judge DECREED that the company had to rehire the two employees.”</p>"
    },
    "LEGIBLE": {
      "word": "LEGIBLE",
      "phonetic": "(lej'-:;i-b:;il)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">readable </p><p> The <i class=“def-ital\">leg</i> part of the word is from a Latin word meaning to <i class=“def-ital\">read</i>. Something which is LEGIBLE is able to be read easily, is clear and plain. </p><p>“Her handwriting was small but LEGIBLE.” </p><p>“The sign was so covered over with dirt that it was barely LEGIBLE.” </p><p>The opposite of LEGIBLE is ILLEGIBLE, <i class=“def-ital\">not readable</i>. </p><p>“He signed his name so quickly that it was completely ILLEGIBLE.” </p><p><i class=“def-ital\">Sensible</i> is often chosen as the meaning of LEGIBLE. Something can be LEGIBLE, however, and not make any sense. </p><p>Other forms of the word: LEGIBILITY, n.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-able</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "GRANDEUR": {
      "word": "GRANDEUR",
      "phonetic": "(gran'-j:)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">greatness, majesty, magnificence, splendor </p><p>GRANDEUR comes from the word <i class=“def-ital\">grand</i>. GRANDEUR is greatness, impressiveness. The word is used about people and things. </p><p>“He admired the GRANDEUR of those ancient kings.” </p><p>“The GRANDEUR of the magnificent scenery left us all in awe.” </p><p>“His ideas had a certain GRANDEUR, but he never had enough money to carry them out.”</p>"
    },
    "ENUNCIATE": {
      "word": "ENUNCIATE",
      "phonetic": "(i-nuhn'-sE-At)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to declare, proclaim, state definitely; pronounce, utter </p><p>ENUNCIATE is from the same Latin word as <i class=“def-ital\">pronunciation</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">renunciation</i>. All have to do with speaking out or declaring something. ENUNCIATE has two somewhat different uses. One meaning is “to state or declare in a formal way.” </p><p>“Jefferson was among the first to ENUNCIATE the principles of representative government.” </p><p>“He ENUNCIATED his grand theory of the universe.” </p><p>The second use is simply to <i class=“def-ital\">pronounce</i>, to <i class=“def-ital\">utter</i>. </p><p>“He ENUNCIATED his words carefully.” </p><p>“You must learn to ENUNCIATE clearly.” </p><p>In both senses the basic idea is <i class=“def-ital\">speaking out</i>. </p><p>Other forms of the word: ENUNCIATION, n.</p>"
    },
    "DECIPHER": {
      "word": "DECIPHER",
      "phonetic": "(di-sl'-far)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to make out the meaning of, decode </p><p>One meaning of the word CIPHER is a <i class=“def-ital\">code</i>. To DECIPHER something is to take it out of its code and make it understandable.  </p><p>“The army DECIPHERED the enemy’s top-secret messages.” </p><p>DECIPHER also means “to make out the meaning of” something difficult to understand or read. </p><p>“He managed to DECIPHER the hastily written note.” </p><p>“They DECIPHERED the faint writing on the cave walls.”</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">de-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    },
    "MERCILESS": {
      "word": "MERCILESS",
      "phonetic": "(mer'-S:)-lgs)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">without mercy, showing no pity, cruel </p><p> A MERCILESS person lacks MERCY or pity. </p><p>“The judge was MERCILESS in punishing criminals.” </p><p>“The other boys laughed MERCILESSLY at John’s attempt to sing.” </p><p>“The boxer kept up his MERCILESS attack until his opponent was knocked out.” </p><p>The opposite of MERCILESS is MERCIFUL, <i class=“def-ital\">full of</i> MERCY. </p><p>“The father decided to be MERCIFUL and not punish his son.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: MERCY, n. MERCIFUL, adj.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-less</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "GLUTTON": {
      "word": "GLUTTON",
      "phonetic": "(gluht'-gn)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a person who eats too much </p><p>To GLUT something is to overfill it, to supply it with more than it needs. </p><p>“There are too many television sets for sale; the market is GLUTTED with them.” </p><p>A GLUTTON eats too much; he stuffs or gorges himself at every meal and always wants more food than is good for him. </p><p>“He was a real GLUTTON; he always had six hamburgers for lunch.” </p><p>GLUTTON can also be used about a person who never seems to have enough of something besides food. A “GLUTTON for punishment” is someone who can take a lot of punishment without giving in. </p><p>Other forms of the word: GLUT, v. GLUTTONY, n. GLUTTONOUS, adj.</p>"
    },
    "ESCAPADE": {
      "word": "ESCAPADE",
      "phonetic": "(es'-kÔøΩpAd)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">an adventure, prank, wild experience </p><p>ESCAPADE is from the same root as <i class=“def-ital\">escape</i>, and an old meaning of ESCAPADE was “an act of escaping.” Today the word has come to mean “an exciting adventure or action which goes against normal behavior.” </p><p>“His trip to Tahiti was a surprising ESCAPADE for such an old man.” </p><p>An ESCAPADE isn’t usually evil, but it can cause trouble. </p><p>“His childish ESCAPADES usually cost us a lot of money.” </p><p>“The foolish ESCAPADE on the boat almost caused them to drown.” </p><p>The most common mistake for the meaning of ESCAPADE is <i class=“def-ital\">crime</i>. An ESCAPADE could be a <i class=“def-ital\">crime</i>, but it generally suggests something less serious.</p>"
    },
    "RANSACK": {
      "word": "RANSACK",
      "phonetic": "(ran'-sak)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to search thoroughly, rifle </p><p>To RANSACK something is to search through it thoroughly. RANSACK usually suggests that the searching is violent or disorderly, or for the purpose of robbery. </p><p>“He RANSACKED the house looking for his mittens.” </p><p>“The jewel thief RANSACKED the vault.” </p><p>“The invaders RANSACKED the city and took everything of value they could find.” </p><p>Many people think RANSACK means <i class=“def-ital\">destroy</i>, probably because of the violence often associated with RANSACKING.</p>"
    },
    "FALTER": {
      "word": "FALTER",
      "phonetic": "(fol'-t:)r)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to hesitate, waver, stumble, stagger </p><p>To FALTER is to waver or hesitate, to act uncertainly out of fear, weakness, or nervousness. </p><p>“He started the speech well, but FALTERED halfway through.” </p><p>“She never FALTERED in her drive to become a successful doctor.” </p><p>“The football team began to FALTER in the second quarter, and by the end of the game couldn’t do anything right.” </p><p>“His legs began to FALTER, and he knew he would never make it to the top of the mountain.” </p><p>The most frequently chosen wrong answer on the Pretest is <i class=“def-ital\">change</i>, probably because FALTER looks like <i class=“def-ital\">alter</i>, which means to <i class=“def-ital\">change</i>.</p>"
    },
    "DISPEL": {
      "word": "DISPEL",
      "phonetic": "(di-spel'",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to drive away, scatter, clear away </p><p> The <i class=“def-ital\">pel</i> part of DISPEL means to <i class=“def-ital\">drive</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">push</i>. To <i class=“def-ital\">impel</i> is to drive <i class=“def-ital\">forward</i>; to <i class=“def-ital\">repel</i> is to drive <i class=“def-ital\">back</i>. To DISPEL is to drive <i class=“def-ital\">away</i>. DISPEL is used more about emotions and states of mind than about actual physical objects. </p><p>“His arguments DISPELLED any remaining doubts they had about the plan.” </p><p>“The teacher DISPELLED any illusions he might have had about passing the course.” </p><p>“Bill’s reassurances couldn’t DISPEL her feeling that someone was following them.”</p>",
      "prefix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">dis-</i> under Prefixes."
      ]
    }
  },
  "id": "1",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "HASTEN to the store.",
          "answers": [
            "walk",
            "return",
            "wander",
            "drive slowly",
            "go quickly"
          ],
          "word": "HASTEN",
          "correct": "go quickly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The FAMINE began.",
          "answers": [
            "problem",
            "disease",
            "food shortage",
            "feast",
            "dust storm"
          ],
          "word": "FAMINE",
          "correct": "food shortage"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Fine EXCURSION.",
          "answers": [
            "visit",
            "holiday",
            "car",
            "journey",
            "recreation"
          ],
          "word": "EXCURSION",
          "correct": "journey"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was DERANGED.",
          "answers": [
            "crazy",
            "dirty",
            "clever",
            "unhappy",
            "late"
          ],
          "word": "DERANGED",
          "correct": "crazy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The expected DECREE.",
          "answers": [
            "understanding",
            "diploma",
            "shout",
            "order",
            "weather"
          ],
          "word": "DECREE",
          "correct": "order"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was LEGIBLE.",
          "answers": [
            "readable",
            "unclear",
            "clean",
            "sensible",
            "well-written"
          ],
          "word": "LEGIBLE",
          "correct": "readable"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The GRANDEUR of ancient Rome.",
          "answers": [
            "buildings",
            "heroes",
            "greatness",
            "legal system",
            "evil"
          ],
          "word": "GRANDEUR",
          "correct": "greatness"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She ENUNCIATES well.",
          "answers": [
            "dresses",
            "speaks",
            "hears",
            "draws",
            "writes"
          ],
          "word": "ENUNCIATE",
          "correct": "speaks"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They DECIPHERED the message.",
          "answers": [
            "decoded",
            "removed",
            "demanded",
            "discovered",
            "sent off"
          ],
          "word": "DECIPHER",
          "correct": "decoded"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MERCILESS men.",
          "answers": [
            "greedy",
            "brave",
            "powerful",
            "cruel",
            "kind"
          ],
          "word": "MERCILESS",
          "correct": "cruel"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were GLUTTONS.",
          "answers": [
            "dieters",
            "comics",
            "cowards",
            "overeaters",
            "drunks"
          ],
          "word": "GLUTTON",
          "correct": "overeaters"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Strange ESCAPADE.",
          "answers": [
            "crime",
            "adventure",
            "silence",
            "comedy",
            "trip"
          ],
          "word": "ESCAPADE",
          "correct": "adventure"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RANSACK the desk.",
          "answers": [
            "destroy",
            "replace",
            "thoroughly search",
            "clean",
            "throw away"
          ],
          "word": "RANSACK",
          "correct": "thoroughly search"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Made him FALTER.",
          "answers": [
            "jump",
            "wonder",
            "change",
            "hesitate",
            "retreat"
          ],
          "word": "FALTER",
          "correct": "hesitate"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISPEL their fears.",
          "answers": [
            "list",
            "cause",
            "disagree with",
            "fight",
            "drive away"
          ],
          "word": "DISPEL",
          "correct": "drive away"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do HASTY decisions take a lot of thought?",
          "word": "HASTEN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would people die during a FAMINE?",
          "word": "FAMINE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If you moved to Japan, would that be an EXCURSION?",
          "word": "EXCURSION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are DERANGED people sometimes dangerous?",
          "word": "DERANGED",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are DECREES usually funny?",
          "word": "DECREE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is this sentence LEGIBLE?",
          "word": "LEGIBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would GRANDEUR usually be a quality of a king's palace?",
          "word": "GRANDEUR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Should an actor be able to ENUNCIATE clearly?",
          "word": "ENUNCIATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it possible to DECIPHER a message sent in a simple code?",
          "word": "DECIPHER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a MERCILESS person take pity on others?",
          "word": "MERCILESS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are GLUTTONS usually overweight?",
          "word": "GLUTTON",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is an ESCAPADE usually boring?",
          "word": "ESCAPADE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you fix a wobbly chair by RANSACKING it?",
          "word": "RANSACK",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If something FALTERS, does it go straight to the end without stopping?",
          "word": "FALTER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can doubts be DISPELLED?",
          "word": "DISPEL",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "George HASTENED to his mother's bedside when he heard that she was dying.",
          "word": "HASTEN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was such a pleasant FAMINE that they decided to do it every week.",
          "word": "FAMINE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They went on a brief EXCURSION into the city one morning.",
          "word": "EXCURSION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He claimed he was DERANGED when he committed the crime and therefore wasn't responsible for his actions.",
          "word": "DERANGED",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The principal DECREED that there would be no running in the school corridors.",
          "word": "DECREE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The teacher refused to accept homework which was not LEGIBLE.",
          "word": "LEGIBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He felt that nothing could compare with the GRANDEUR of the Rocky Mountains.",
          "word": "GRANDEUR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The founder ENUNCIATED the rules by which the organization would be governed.",
          "word": "ENUNCIATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He had such poor handwriting that it was impossible to DECIPHER his letters.",
          "word": "DECIPHER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The author was upset by the MERCILESS criticism of his new book.",
          "word": "MERCILESS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was such a GLUTTON that he couldn't go two steps without tripping.",
          "word": "GLUTTON",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "On Halloween all the children joined in various harmless ESCAPADES.",
          "word": "ESCAPADE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "During the battle we RANSACKED the enemy with our bombers.",
          "word": "RANSACK",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I couldn't FALTER him for the way he acted; I would have done the same thing myself.",
          "word": "FALTER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The senator tried to DISPEL the rumors that he was running for president.",
          "word": "DISPEL",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "HASTEN",
          "answers": [
            "rush",
            "hurry",
            "escape"
          ],
          "word": "HASTEN",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FAMINE",
          "answers": [
            "illness",
            "hunger",
            "starvation"
          ],
          "word": "FAMINE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXCURSION",
          "answers": [
            "journey",
            "digression",
            "surprise"
          ],
          "word": "EXCURSION",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DERANGED",
          "answers": [
            "crazy",
            "mad",
            "bitter"
          ],
          "word": "DERANGED",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DECREE",
          "answers": [
            "law",
            "suggestion",
            "regulation"
          ],
          "word": "DECREE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LEGIBLE",
          "answers": [
            "real",
            "plain",
            "clear"
          ],
          "word": "LEGIBLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GRANDEUR",
          "answers": [
            "sweetness",
            "riches",
            "brilliance"
          ],
          "word": "GRANDEUR",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENUNCIATE",
          "answers": [
            "declare",
            "laugh",
            "speak"
          ],
          "word": "ENUNCIATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DECIPHER",
          "answers": [
            "decode",
            "repeat",
            "understand"
          ],
          "word": "DECIPHER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MERCILESS",
          "answers": [
            "tremendous",
            "pitiless",
            "ferocious"
          ],
          "word": "MERCILESS",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GLUTTON",
          "answers": [
            "fugitive",
            "gorger",
            "hog"
          ],
          "word": "GLUTTON",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ESCAPADE",
          "answers": [
            "fun",
            "excitement",
            "terror"
          ],
          "word": "ESCAPADE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RANSACK",
          "answers": [
            "pack",
            "hunt",
            "look for"
          ],
          "word": "RANSACK",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FALTER",
          "answers": [
            "stumble",
            "question",
            "hesitate"
          ],
          "word": "FALTER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DISPEL",
          "answers": [
            "clear",
            "scatter",
            "hurt"
          ],
          "word": "DISPEL",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}